Mahmood Athil

Senior Technical Support Engineer

Email

mahmoodathil24@outlook.com

Phone

+91 63790 70771

Location Chennai, IN

Experienced Senior Technical Support Engineer in IT Corporate Environment. Enthusiastic to work with modern tools for Automation and Productivity, and related technologies. Currently skilled & challenged in Web Development, Infra Technologies and Azure Cloud. Excited to handle opportunities with relevance to Cloud Technologies & DevOps practices.

Profiles

LinkedIn GitHub mahmood-athil madwavl

Experience

Genpact

April 2023 - Present

Technical Support (Develooer Support Engineer)

Supported Products (Meta's APIs & SDKs) and its Use-Cases. Dogfooding New Featured Releases. And Communicate Feature Requests - Maintaining Weekly Metrics

- Assisted on Troubleshooting Product Issues with L2s/L3s/SWEs & with Account/Partner Managers (Full Time Meta Employees) on updating bug resolution for High Tiered Partners
- Create Custom Test Environments, around SDKs and APIs to Debug Common Bugs Reported via Tickets
- Document Use-Cases, Bugs, Upcoming Features as Wiki or a Knowledge Base Article
- Promoted as Subject Matter Expert (on a span of 3 months)

- Improved Customer Satisfaction for L1 Supported Tickets thorugh a Green-Belt Project Improved Response Rate from 5% to 13% and Overall Customer Satisfaction from 28% to 62%
- Dogfood (Testing & Debug) Upcoming/Beta Application Features Requests
- Work Closely with Meta Partner Managers on attempting to resolve Partner Queries
- Use Microsoft Excel/Google Sheets Formulas for Automating Data Capture (via Dashboards) and Root Cause Analysis for Client Review Meetings
- SQL Queries to export custom data from Log Tables (Scuba)
- Utilized Internal Tools Bots, Project Management Tool For Daily Business-As-Usual Tasks
- Handle Client/Partner Escalations for Missed Resolution, though managing Same-Tier Resolution at around 82%

Hilane Digital

June 2022 - February 2023

Technical Support Engineer

Maintained Operations of Significance for the

- Create UI Components in Pure JavaScript + React / Scripts based off JavaScript for Business Use Cases
- Creating Scripts (PowerShell) to automate Manual System Tasks
- Analyzing & Maintain Records of new Hardware & Software Assets
- Maintain Azure AD and Monthly Subscription / Payment Reports

Tech Mahindra

November 2019 - May 2022

Application Support Engineer

Managed IT Support Operations for Project with Digi Telecommunication (Pvt. Ltd.), Malaysia

- Implemented & Maintained ITIL solutions Resolving Incidents & Service Requests (Maintaining 90% SLAs on First Call without escalations)
- Analyse Requirements and Business Use-cases of Application Integration with Organization's Regular Workflow
- Use SQL Queries for Creating Custom Reports via Izenda Reporting Tool
- Test & Troubleshoot APIs for SMS Management (Twilio) & Chatbot Facilities
- Maintain Application Servers (Windows Server 2012 & Ubunutu Server LTS)
 Check on recurring errors through application log and ensure 24/7
 service & Connection Availability throughout Digi Infrastructure.
- Build & Define process with Infra Teams for further server/network device integration, through monitoring account creation WMI, SSH (for Server) & SNMP Based Monitoring via MIB OIDs (for the Network Devices)
- Create BASH / PowerShell Scripts to troubleshoot monitoring issues

Skills

Web Development Beginner

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript

Server Administration Beginner

- Windows Server 2019
- Ubunutu Server
- RHEL

Version Control Systems Scripting Beginner

- Git
- Github

Intermediate

- Bash
- Powershell
- Python

IT Insfrastructure Library Beginner

- Service Management
- Asset Management
- Operations Management

API Testing Beginner

- Postman
- Facebook's Graph API Explorer

Volunteer

Bhumi

2018 - 2019

Chapter Coordinator

Top NGO - promotes whole-school transformations and gives educational opportunities to students from disadvantaged communities.

- Managed Volunteer Teams and enhanced volunteering experience organizing Events & Programs
- Teaching Underprivileged Children from Schools & Orphanages about Computer Science and Information Technology
- Organizing Events to Embrace Learning (Math & Computer Science) among Communities

Education

2015 - 2019

Dhaanish Ahmed College of Engineering Engineering (Petroleum)

Awards

Ace - Silver Award **April 16, 2024** Genpact

On Handling Major Organizational Events. Coordinating Programs & Managing Volunteering Projects as a Coordinator

Bhumi's Changemaker Award **April 16, 2024**Bhumi - NGO

On Handling Major Organizational Events. Coordinating Programs & Managing Volunteering Projects as a Coordinator

Languages

Tamil
Native speaker

English *Professional*

Interests

Embedded Technologies

- Internet of Things
- 3D-Printing

Android & Web Development

- Kotlin
- Android Open Source Project
- React
- Flutter

Cloud Operations

- AWS
- Azure